<bill session="115" type="sr" number="18" updated="2018-09-19T14:20:24Z">
  <state datetime="2017-05-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution reaffirming the United States-Argentina partnership and recognizing Argentina's economic reforms.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution reaffirming the United States-Argentina partnership and recognizing Argentina's economic reforms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2017-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2017-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2017-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S404"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-06-05">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Corker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-06-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="114">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 114.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral" name="Senate Foreign Relations" code="SSFR" subcommittee=""/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" relation="unknown" number="54" type="hr"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Argentina"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-06-05T14:46:34Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Declares that the Senate:

 upholds its commitment to the partnership between the United States and Argentina and reaffirms that Argentina is a major U.S. ally; encourages the Department of State to coordinate an interagency strategy to increase cooperation with the government of Argentina on areas of bilateral, regional, and global concern; commends President Mauricio Macri and his Administration for making far-reaching economic reforms; encourages efforts to promote inclusive economic growth and reduce inequality; encourages such government to continue to investigate and prosecute those responsible for the 1994 bombing of the Argentine-Israeli Mutual Association (AMIA) in Buenos Aires and the death of AMIA special prosecutor Alberto Nisman; expresses its desire that the growing partnership between the United States and Argentina will result in greater cooperation at multilateral institutions; and supports the continuing implementation of the United States Trade and Investment Framework Agreement with Argentina and Argentina's efforts toward greater integration with the global economy.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
