<bill session="115" type="sr" number="5" updated="2018-09-19T14:20:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate in support of Israel.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate in support of Israel.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2017-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2017-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral" name="Senate Foreign Relations" code="SSFR" subcommittee=""/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-03T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Urges: (1) the President and the international community to join in supporting bilateral talks between the Israelis and Palestinians, and (2) the President to adopt a policy of opposing and vetoing if necessary one-sided Security Council resolutions targeting Israel.

Expresses support for individuals and organizations working to bring about peace and cooperation between the Israelis and Palestinians. Calls on all parties to return to negotiations without preconditions.

Opposes the use of the United Nations to impose external remedies to challenges between the Israelis and Palestinians. Objects to the December 2016 abstention and declination by the United States to veto U.N. Security Council Resolution 2334. (Such resolution characterizes Israeli settlements in the West Bank and East Jerusalem as illegal and demands cessation of settlement activities.)

Declares that the Senate regrets and seeks to reverse the negative public criticism of Israel by U.S. diplomats.

Rejects international efforts to delegitimize Israel's right to exist. Expresses support for Israel's right to self-defense. Condemns acts of terrorism and violence targeted at Israeli civilians. Reiterates that Palestinian political goals will never be achieved through violence.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
