<bill session="115" type="sr" number="23" updated="2018-09-19T14:20:25Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution establishing the Select Committee on Cybersecurity.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution establishing the Select Committee on Cybersecurity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2017-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2017-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S453-454"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral" name="Senate Rules and Administration" code="SSRA" subcommittee=""/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-24T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Establishes the Senate Select Committee on Cybersecurity to oversee and make continuing studies of, and recommendations regarding, cybersecurity threats to the United States. The committee: (1) may report by bill or otherwise on matters within its jurisdiction; and (2) shall be referred all proposed legislation and other matters concerning domestic and foreign cybersecurity risks (including state-sponsored threats), federal agency cybersecurity activities, the organization or reorganization of agencies relating to cybersecurity threats or incidents, and authorizations for appropriations relating to protecting against cybersecurity threats and relevant incidents or actions.

Directs agencies to keep the select committee informed, and furnish the committee requested information, about cybersecurity activities, threats, and any significant anticipated activities.

Requires the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, the Central Intelligence Agency, the Department of Defense, the Department of State, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Department of Commerce to each submit to the select committee an annual report on cyber threats.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
