<bill session="115" type="sr" number="11" updated="2018-09-19T14:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution encouraging the development of best business practices to fully utilize the potential of the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution encouraging the development of best business practices to fully utilize the potential of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2017-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2017-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2017-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2017-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee activity="Referral" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" code="SSHR" subcommittee=""/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" relation="unknown" number="77" type="hr"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-01-10T05:00:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Encourages each corporate, academic, and social entity: (1) to develop an internal rule modeled after a successful business practice, such as the Rooney Rule (requires every National Football League team with a coach or general manager opening to interview at least one minority candidate) or the RLJ Rule (encourages companies to voluntarily establish a best practices policy to identify minority candidates and vendors by implementing a plan to interview at least two qualified minority candidates for managerial openings at the director level and above and to interview two qualified minority businesses before approving a vendor contract); (2) in accordance with title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, to adapt that rule to specifications that will best fit the procedures of the individual entity; and (3) to institute such individualized rule to ensure that the entity will always consider candidates from underrepresented populations before selecting a business vendor or filling a leadership position.</summary>
  <committee-reports/>
</bill>
